Lyla Mendoza

lyla-mendoza.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode

Location: Anycity, Anystate, Anycountry Email: lyla@gmail.com | Mobile: 5555555555

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled web developer with over **3 years of experience** in **HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **React, Angular, and Vue.js** and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, PHP, Java, HTML, CSS
Frameworks : React.js, Angular, Express, Node.js
Libraries : Material, Redux, React Router

Databases : MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Gitlab

EXPERIENCE

Web DeveloperApr 2022 – PresentAnycompanyRemote – AnyCity, Anystate, Anycountry

• Designed and developed dynamic and responsive websites using **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **and PHP**

• Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from databases

• Improved website performance and speed through optimization techniques by 55%

Backend Developer

Anycompany

Aug 2021 – Nov 2022 Anycity, Anystate, Anycountry

Worked with MVC frameworks to develop robust and scalable backends

Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend to ensure smooth operation of the applications

Backend Developer Intern

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

• Assisted senior web developers in the design and development of websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

EDUCATION

University of Anystate

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Anycity, Anystate, Anycountry Jan 2016 – Dec 2020

PROJECTS

Project 1 React.js, Redux, PHP, MySQL Git Source Code

- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Optimized website for speed and user experience
- Utilized responsive design to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

Project 2 Node.js, Express, JavaScript, Git Source Code

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with Node.js
- Exposed POST, GET, PATCH and DELETE HTTP methods using Express

CERTIFICATIONS

- · Certified Web Developer by the W3C
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate
- · AWS Certified Developer Associate